http://www.bap.org/privacy

Beta Alpha Psi Privacy Policy
Contact&bulletReporting Intranet
AboutHistory and Leadership100th Anniversary TimelineBoard of DirectorsChapter AdvocatesProfessional PartnersStaffVision, Mission, Constitution & BylawsAbout Beta Alpha PsiConstitution & BylawsAnnual Report & Strategic PrioritiesAnnual ReportStrategic PrioritiesBAP Impact videoResourcesBoard ResourcesChapter Advocate ResourcesProfessional Partner ResourcesBenefitsQuick LinksChapter ResourcesReporting Intranet ResourcesMemberMember BenefitsBenefits provided by Professional PartnersBenefits from Professional Partners during COVID-19Pre-Recorded Sessions for Fall 2020AlumniAlumni & Member NetworkRegional Alumni RepresentativesExecutive Graduate Honor (EGH)Executive Graduate HonorImpactGiving Back in the Next 100Community ImpactRecognitionQuick LinksDeadlines CalendarEvents CalendarCompetition & AwardsCompetition and Award DescriptionsPrevious Winners2020 Winners2019 WinnersNews & CalendarsNewsQuarterly newsletter & Press releases2020 Annual ReportDeadlines CalendarNominations, Competitions and Awards ReportingEvents CalendarMeetingsResourcesChapter ResourcesIncludes materials to manage your BAP chapter effectively!Chapter ResourcesFaculty Advisors ResourcesIncludes materials for all faculty advisors (existing and new) to maintain a strong and effective chapter.Faculty Advisor ResourcesReporting Intranet ResourcesIncludes training and FAQ materials on all aspects of Chapter Reporting.Reporting Intranet ResourcesBoard of Directors ResourcesIncludes materials for all current International BAP Board of Directors.Board of Directors ResourcesChapter Advocate ResourcesIncludes materials for all current Chapter Advocates.Chapter Advocate ResourcesProfessional Partner ResourcesIncludes materials for all Professional Partners.Professional Partner ResourcesJoinQuick LinksChapter ResourcesMembership BenefitsActive ChaptersStart a chapterPetitioning Process/Start a chapterChapter ActivitiesBAP Impact videoJoinJoinMembership BenefitsEligibilityFind a chapterAbout Beta Alpha Psi
Beta Alpha Psi Privacy Policy
Privacy Policy Form - Candidates
Privacy Policy Form - Current Members
1. PRIVACY NOTICE
Beta Alpha Psi (BAP) is committed to protecting your privacy. The following policy discloses our procedures surrounding this commitment.
The Beta Alpha Psi (BAP) Privacy Notice is effective as of 08/2011. The use of the websites and services offered by the BAP constitutes your acceptance of the Privacy Notice. If you use the website, register, apply, join, participate or otherwise submit personally identifiable information, you are consenting to the use of such data in accordance with this Privacy Notice. If you are an international user, the use of any website covered by this Privacy Notice constitutes consent to this Privacy Notice and an acknowledgement that use of any website covered by the Privacy Notice is solely subject to the laws governing the use of data in the United States.
This Privacy Policy covers the privacy practices of all USA, Australian and New Zealand chapters. Other foreign chapters depending on where they are located, may be subject to different laws and requirements than those of USA, Australia and New Zealand chapters. (To understand how chapters in others jurisdiction use personal information, please contact them directly). European chapters and any information pertaining to EU participants are covered by this policy and the Addendum to this policy.
2. ORGANIZATIONAL OVERVIEW
BAP is an honorary organization for Financial Information students and professionals. The primary objective of Beta Alpha Psi is to encourage and give recognition to scholastic and professional excellence in the business information field. This includes promoting the study and practice of accounting, finance and information systems; providing opportunities for self- development, service and association among members and practicing professionals, and encouraging a sense of ethical, social, and public responsibility.
BAP operates a Web site under the URL http://www.bap.org.
3. SCOPE OF POLICY
This Privacy Policy governs the privacy practices used by BAP on its Web site as well as its offline data collection, use, and disclosure activities.
The Web Site may contain links to Web sites not under BAP’s control and managed by third parties with independent information and privacy practices. It is your responsibility to read the privacy policies of the site to which you are redirected before supplying any personal information. In addition, we have no control over information that is submitted to, or collected by, these third parties. Accordingly, you should consult these other Web sites' privacy policies when accessing or using such other Web pages.
4. INFORMATION COLLECTION
We collect information from you when you are registered as a member on our site or BAP Community online, register for a conference, subscribe to our newsletter, donate to BAP, enter competitions and/or receive a prize or award or fill out a form.
Information Automatically Logged
BAP may make a record of your visit and logs any of the following information for statistical and business purposes - the user's server address, the user's domain name, IP address, the date and time of the visit, the pages accessed and documents downloaded, the previous site visited and the type of browser used.
If you are not a BAP member and you send us a message, BAP will record your e-mail address.
Security Information
BAP sites have security measures in place to protect against the loss, misuse, and alteration of the information. This is not considered to be a guarantee of protection of your information. A login name and password are required to visit secure areas, and before personal information (such as Reporting Intranet) are published on the site, visitors are required to enter their member login as well. This is to ensure that the information is displayed only to the intended person. You should ensure that any password is kept securely and cannot be discovered by anyone else.
Cookies
A cookie is information that a Web site puts on your hard disk so that it can remember something about you at a later time. (More technically, it is information for future use that is stored by the server on the client side of a client/server communication.) It is possible to disable the accepting of cookies by your web browser, however doing so may restrict your ability to access some web pages.
Some sites are access restricted. These sites may use cookies to deliver content specific to your interest. Cookies may also be used for authentication purposes, and to improve security during a visitor's session online.
Cookies may store the following information: session (numbered key) and duration. A numbered key is a unique server generated number used to identify the current session. The session key can be linked back to a user's login identification.
Unique identifiers (such as login identification) are collected from Web site visitors to verify the user's identity, and for use as account numbers in our record system.
Surveys
All academic / research surveys conducted by BAP staff and / or students, which involve the collection of personal information, will have received approval from the Board of Directors.
Some of our online surveys ask visitors for unique identifiers (like login identification).
Contact information from the surveys may be used to get in touch with the visitor when necessary, for example to follow up on any issues identified by the visitor.
Registration Forms
If personal information is collected via a website this will be done by sufficiently secure means. Where personal information is collected by local chapters, that information will be carefully used and stored.
For certain applications, registration forms require users to give contact information (like name and email address), and unique identifiers (like login identification).
5. WHAT INFORMATION IS COLLECTED
5.1 – Personal information collected on the Reporting Intranet:
Name
Address
Phone
Email
Candidate Start Date
Initiation Date
School
Membership Type (Undergraduate, Graduate, Faculty or Honorary)
Major (Accounting, Finance or Information Systems)
Membership Status
Ethnicity (optional)
Gender (optional)
Birth Date (optional)
5.2 – Personal Information collected on the BAP Online Community site
Name
Address
Phone
Email
Initiation Date
Graduation Date
School
Membership Type (Member, Alumni, Board Member, Advisory Forum Member or BAP Staff)
Employer
Title
Certifications
Opt Out:
My Alma Mater
Colleges/University
Members
Alumni
Opt In
Regional Meetings
National Activities
5.3 – Personal Information collected on the Meeting and Conferences Registration System
First Name
Last Name
Nickname
Email
Registration Type
School or Firm
Work Address – use as primary
Home Address – use as primary
Regional Meetings that will be attended
Payment information (Credit Card Information)
Guest Information (name)
5.3.1 – Meeting and Conferences Registration System – Annual Meeting
All information from above including:
KPMG – Community Service Day Online Waiver (Release of name, photo and liability risks)
T-Shirt Size
Student Volunteer Hub
Name
Email Contact
Which volunteer event they will monitor
5.3.2 – Meeting and Conference Registration System – International
All information from above including:
Local Community Service Day Online Waiver (Release of name, photo and liability risks)
T-Shirt Size
Student Volunteer Hub
Name
Email Contact
Which volunteer event they will monitor
5.4 – Access Database – Executive Office
Non-Chapter Contact Information – Board, Advisory Forum Members, Vendors and Staff
Name
BAP Title
Job Title
Employer
Address
Email
Phone
Fax
Payment Information via PayPal
5.6 – BAP Website – BAP Store – Certificate and Award Order Form information
Replacement Certificates
School
Chapter Number/Name
First and Last Name
Initiation Date
Faculty advisor First and Last Name
Ship to address
Award Certificates
Ship to address
5.7 – BAP Website – Competitions and Downloadable Forms Page
Gold Challenge – KPMG – Nomination Form
School
Chapter Name
Chapter President Name
Faculty Advisor First and Last Name
Faculty Advisor Phone
Faculty Advisor Email
Competition Verification Information
Gold Challenge – KPMG Release Form – Consent of Personal data and likeness release.
Name/Title
School
Chapter Name
Signature
Date
Project Run With It
Nomination Form
Last Name
First Name
Email Address
Cell Phone
Chapter Officer/Member/Candidate
Overall GPA
Major
Confirmation that the nominee will attend the annual meeting
Confirmation of registration
Confirmation that the nominee has read all PRWI competition guidelines
Confirmation that the nominee will participate fully in annual meeting events and will arrive in time for the start of the PRWI competition.
Confirmation that the nominee has completed the NFP pre-competition requirements
Confirmation that nominee has signed confidentiality agreement
Confirmation that nominee agrees to image, photo and video release
Polo Shirt size
University Name
Chapter name and number
Faculty Advisor name and contact information
Will FA be attending the annual meeting?
Confidentiality Agreement
Signature
Name
Email
Cell phone
University
Chapter Number
Date
University/Firm/Employer Name
Region (if applicable)
Photo
Bio of Presidents
Advisory Forum Members
Name
Title
Employer
State
Photo
Business Information Professional of the Year Recipients
Name
Employer
Category of Award (Education, Industry & Government, Professional Services)
Bio
Photo
International Scholars
Names of students who presented at regional and annual meetings
First Name
Last Name
Presentation Acronym (PRWI, BP/RM, BP/AM, RM, AM)
Outstanding Faculty Advisor Winners
Name
University
Region
Photo
Outstanding Chapter Information
Chapter Number
Charter Year
Number of Initiates for FY XXXX
Chapter Name
School Name
Faculty Advisor First and Last Name, Co-Advisor First and Last Name
Chapter President(s) First and Last Name
Chapter Award Status (Distinguished, Superior, Significantly Improved, Most Improved, Gold Chapter)
Annual Meeting Winners for all competitions
University Name
Chapter Name
First and Last Name of student/FA winners
Executive Office Staff
Name
Title
Bio
First and Last Name
Affiliation (Firm or University)
User signs up with:
Email
Password
5.9 Discussion forum
User details will be collected.
6. WHAT DO WE USE INFORMATION FOR and WHO USES THE INFORMATION
Any of the information we collect from you may be used in one of the following ways:
To contact you about membership or potential membership
To improve service (your information helps us to more effectively respond to your requests and support needs
To process transactions
To administer a contest, promotion, survey or other site feature
To send periodic emails
Specifically:
6.1 – Personal information collected on the Reporting Intranet
Role: Chapter Officers, Faculty Advisor & Administrator
Information collected through the Reporting Intranet is solely used to help chapters manage their chapter membership and reporting activities. The Internet information is also used to determine some competition results. The role of the Administrator is to reconcile payments to the membership records and to help in the updating of the membership status when candidates have become initiated.
6.2 – Personal Information collected on the BAP Online Community site
Role: Individual, Administrator
The information collected on the BAP Online Community is solely used by Beta Alpha Psi in updating records for members who are interested while members and for members who have graduated and have moved onto alumni status and to use this information in reaching out to alumni to garner interest in upcoming regional meetings to participate on alumni panels as a potential professional speaker.
Individuals will have access to the system by registering online and creating a unique login ID and password that only they will know. Individuals will have access to viewing and updating their records only. Administrator will query only opt in email contacts to send out invites to alumni events (newsletter, regional meetings and alumni meetings).
6.3 – Personal Information collected on the Meeting and Conferences Registration System
Role: Individual, Conference Planner, Supervisor, Conference Operations
Information collected is used to administer and run conferences. The information is used by the AICPA Conference Planners and BAP staff in the running of conferences.
Organizing chapters of conferences will have access to information as required by the individual needs of the conference being organized.
6.4 – Access Database – Executive Office
Role: Administrator
Information collected will be used for BAP operations.
6.5 – BAP Website – Donations Screen
Role: Individual and Administrator
Information collected will be used to verify the donation. With consent, donations may publicized to acknowledge generosity. Information from donations will be added to the newsletter and alumni databases if not already within the databases.
6.6– BAP Website – BAP Store – Certificate and Award Order Form information
Role: Individual and Administrator
Information collected will be used for BAP operations only.
6.7 – BAP Website – Competitions and Downloadable Forms Page
Role: Individual, Administrator, Board Members and Advisory Forum Members, Judges
Information collected will be used to administer and run competitions. Information will used by BAP staff to administer the competitions and by Judges to carry out and adjudicate the competition. Winners of competition will be published in the BAP web site and other sources with consent of the competitors.
6.8 – Annual Report
Role: Administrator, Graphic Design Department
Information collected will be used for publication in the Annual Report.
6.9 Discussion forum
7. HOW DO WE PROTECT INFORMATION
We implement a variety of security measures to maintain the safety of your personal information when you enter, submit, or access your personal information. Our staff is trained to treat information with the utmost confidentiality. Internally, we restrict access to personal information to employees and contractors and agents who need access to the information to do their jobs or perform services on behalf of BAP. This is not considered to be a guarantee of protection of your information.
We offer the use of a secure server. All supplied sensitive/credit information is transmitted via Secure Socket Layer (SSL) technology and then encrypted into our Database to be only accessed by those authorized with special access rights to our systems, and are required to keep the information confidential.
After a transaction, your information may be kept on file in order to build alumni databases and for further reporting. All other information will be retained until no longer required for operational use and then securely destroyed. (See retention and destruction document).
8. DO WE DISCLOSE ANY INFORMATION TO OUTSIDE PARTIES?
We do not sell, trade, or otherwise transfer to outside parties your personally identifiable information without consent. This does not include trusted third parties who assist us in operating our website, conducting our business, or servicing you, so long as those parties agree to keep this information confidential. We may also release your information when we believe release is appropriate to comply with the law, enforce our site policies, or protect ours or others rights, property, or safety. However, non-personally identifiable information may be provided to other parties for marketing, advertising, or other uses.
Public Forums
BAP may have chat rooms, forums, message boards, social media, and/or newsgroups available to its users. Please remember that any information that is disclosed in these areas becomes public information and you should exercise caution when deciding to disclose your personal information.
California Online Privacy Protection Act Compliance
Because we value your privacy we have taken the necessary precautions to be in compliance with the California Online Privacy Protection Act. We therefore will not distribute your personal information to outside parties without your consent.
You can contact your chapter reporter and view and correct the information or contact executive office and view and correct the information.
9. OPTING OUT
If you supply BAP with your postal address, phone number, or e-mail address, you may receive periodic communications from BAP or other reputable companies affiliated with BAP. The communications will provide information on available services or upcoming events.
If you do not wish to receive such communications from BAP or from the reputable companies affiliated with BAP, you can opt out of receiving them by contacting us at bap@bap.org. You can also opt out of receiving future e-mail messages by following the "unsubscribe" instructions at the bottom of any e-mailed message you receive.
Please allow at least 10 days for your opt-out election to take effect.
You will not be opted out from communication regarding your membership, payment or other similar account management communications or outreach.
10. QUALITY
Checking Your Data on File with the Organizations
Individuals are responsible for providing accurate and complete personal information, and for contacting us if correction of such information is required.
BAP members can request access to the membership information BAP has collected on them or have factual inaccuracies in this information corrected by contacting us at bap@bap.org.
11. TERMS AND CONDITIONS
Please also visit our Terms and Conditions section establishing the use, disclaimers, and limitations of liability governing the use of our website at http://www.bap.org.
12. CONTACTING US
If there are any questions regarding this privacy policy you may contact us using the information below.
Privacy Point of Contact: Chapter Services Specialist
Office: 220 Leigh Farm Road, Durham, NC 27707
Phone: (919) 402-4001
Email: bap@bap.org
System Manager: Web Developer
Office: 220 Leigh Farm Road, Durham, NC 27707
Phone: (919) 402-4080
Email: bap@bap.org
Addendum
1. Purpose of this notice
This Privacy Notice provides mandatory information as required under Articles 13 and 14 of the European General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR) regarding the transparency of personal data processing. Definitions of certain terms within this notice are explained in the appendix.
2. The Data Controller for personal data
The Data Controller for the personal data processed by us is The Executive Office of Beta Alpha Psi. The Data Controller will use that personal data to facilitate membership and membership activities for members and candidates and interested parties in Beta Alpha Psi. Beta Alpha Psi also acts as a Data Controller for any personal data held regarding its own employees, and legally processes this data under its Contract of Employment with those Data Subjects.
3. Your Rights
As a Data Subject you have rights under the GDPR. These rights can bee seen below. Beta Alpha Psi will always fully respect your rights regarding the processing of your personal data, and has provided below the details of the person to contact if you have any concerns or questions regarding how we process your data, or if you wish to exercise any rights you have under the GDPR.
4. Contact Details
The identity and contact detail for the Data Protection Officer within Beta Alpha Psi is:
Office: 220 Leigh Farm Road, Durham, NC 27707
Phone: (919) 402-4080
Email: bap@bap.org
5. Data Protection Principles
Beta Alpha Psi has adopted the following principles to govern its collection and processing of Personal Data:
Personal Data shall be processed lawfully, fairly, and in a transparent manner.
The Personal Data collected will only be those specifically required to fulfill membership activities and requirements. Such data may be collected directly from the Data Subject or provided to Beta Alpha Psi via chapters. Such data will only be processed for that purpose.
Personal Data shall only be retained for as long as it is required to fulfill membership requirements and activities, or to provide statistics to Beta Alpha Psi.
Personal Data shall be adequate, relevant, and limited to what is necessary in relation to the purposes for which they are collected and/or processed. Personal Data shall be accurate and, where necessary, kept up to date.
The Data Subject has the right to request from Beta Alpha Psi access to and rectification or erasure of their personal data, to object to or request restriction of processing concerning the data, or to the right to data portability. In each case such a request must be put in writing as in Section 3 above. The Data Subject has the right to make a complaint directly to a supervisory authority within their own country. Beta Alpha Psi's Data Protection compliance is supervised by:
Office: 220 Leigh Farm Road, Durham, NC 27707
Phone: (919) 402-4080
Email: bap@bap.org
Personal Data shall only be processed based on the legal basis explained in Section 2 above, except where such interests are overridden by the fundamental rights and freedoms of the Data Subject which will always take precedent. If the Data SUbject has provided specific additional Consent to the processing, then such consent may be withdrawn at any time (but may then result in an inability to fulfill membership requirements).
6. Transfers to Third Parties
Membership requirements and activities mean that for most part no data is transferred to third parties. Certain specific activities, such as digital badges and other similar activities, will involve the processing of personal data via a third party. Personal Data shall only be transferred to, or processed by, third party companies where such companies are necessary for the fullfilment of the membership requirement or activity.
Personal Data shall not be transferred to a country or territory outside of the European Economic Area (EEA) unless the transfer is made with the consent of the Data Subject or is made to satisfy the Legitimate Interest of Beta Alpha Psi in regard to its contractual arrangements with its members and candidates.
Appendix - Definitions of certain terms referred to above:
Personal Data: (Article 4 of the GDPR): 'personal data' means any information relating to an identified or identifiable natural person ('data subject'); an identifiable natural person is one who can be identified, directly or indirectly, in particular by reference to an identifier such as a name, an identification number, location data, an online identifier or to one or more factors specific to the physical, physiological, genetic, mental, economic, cultural or social identity of that natural person.
Processing: (Article 4 of the GDPR): means any operation or set of operations which is performed upon personal data or sets of personal data, whether or not by automated means, such as collection, recording, organization, structuring, storage, adaptation or alteration, retrieval, consultation, use, disclosure by transmission, dissemination or otherwise making available, alignment or combination, erasure or destruction.
Legal Basis for Processing: (Article 6 of the GDPR): At least one of these must apply whenever personal data is processed:
Consent: the individual has given clear consent for the processing of their personal data for a specific purpose.
Contract: the processing is necessary for compliance with a contract.
Legal obligation: the processing is necessary to comply with the law (not including contractual obligations).
Vital interests: the processing is necessary to protect someone's life.
Public task: the processing is necessary to perform a task in the public interest, and the task or function has a clear basis in law.
Legitimate interests: the processing is necessary for the legitimate interests of the Data Controller unless there is a good reason to protect the individual's personal data which overrides those legitimate interests.
Data Controller: (Article 4 of the GDPR): this means the person or company that determines the purposes and the means of processing personal data.
Data Processor: (Article 4 of the GDPR): means a natural or legal person, public authority, agency or any other body which processes personal data on behalf of the controller.
Data Subject Rights: (Article 3 of the GDPR): each Data Subject has eight rights. These are:
The right to be informed; This means anyone processing your personal data must make clear what they are processing, why and who else the data may be passed to.
The right of access; this is your right to see what data is held about you by a Data Controller.
The right to rectification; the right to have your data corrected or amended if what is held is incorrect in some way.
The right to erasure; under certain circumstances you can ask for your personal data to be deleted. This is also called 'the Right to be Forgotten'. This would apply if the personal data is no longer required for the purposes it was collected for, or your consent for the processing of that data has been withdrawn, or the personal data has been unlawfully processed.
The right to restrict processing; this gives the Data Subject the right toa sk for a temporary halt to processing of personal data, such as in the case where a dispute or legal case has to be concluded, or the data is being corrected.
The right to data portability; a Data Subject has the right toa sk for any data supplied directly to the Data Controller by him or her, to be provided in a structured, commonly used, and machine-readable format.
The right to object; the Data Subject has the right to object to further processing of their data which is inconsistent with the primary purpose for which it was collected, including profiling, automation, and direct marketing.
Rights in relation to automated decision making and profiling; Data Subjects have the right not to be subject to a decision based solely on automated processing.
Alumni & Member NetworkBenefits from Professional PartnersReporting IntranetAbout UsFounded in 1919, Beta Alpha Psi is an honor organization for financial information students and professionals. There are over 300 chapters on college and university campuses with over 300,000 members initiated since Beta Alpha Psi's formation. All of our chapters are AACSB and/or EQUIS accredited. We are not a fraternity or sorority but an honors organization.2020 Annual ReportThroughout this report, you will find that Beta Alpha Psi is proud of the members, alumni, faculty advisors, Professional Partners, Board of Directors, Chapter Advocates and every volunteer that contributes to the success of this organization. Learn More Here.Connect With Us
Hear what our Professional Partners think about BAP!Each academic year, Becker seeks out college students that are outgoing, engaged, and strong academic performers to represent us as Ambassadors.
When we see a potential candidate is a BAP member, we know they excel in all of these attributes!Michael BrownBecker Professional EducationTotal Chapters300+Total Members300,000+LinksContact UsPrivacyTerms of Use© Copyright 2020 Beta Alpha PSI
